本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
嘿  Charlie  我是你姐姐Teddy
Hey, Charlie! It's your big sister Teddy
我又在拍最新的视频日记了
with the latest installment of my video diary.
Teddy  把那玩意儿关了  现在正吃早饭呢
Teddy, turn that thing off. It's breakfast time.
马上就好了
In a minute!
你听到的噪音来自咱邻居新养的那条特吵的狗
That noise you hear is our neighbor's annoying new dog.
自从她养了那小混球
Ever since she got that little rat,
我们一家就没睡好过觉
none of us have gotten any sleep.
Teddy  我已经告诉你要做什么了
Teddy, I asked you to do something.
我听到啦  不就一分钟嘛
And I asked for a minute!
你的早餐要凉了
Your breakfast is getting cold.
那就把它再放回烤箱不就行了
Well, then just put it back in the toaster!
很抱歉让你看到这一段
Sorry you had to see that.
这里面的赠品呢  本来应该有个小赠品的
There is no prize in here. There's supposed to be a prize.
你昨天就把它拿出来了
You took it out yesterday.
我知道啊  可我不是又放回去了吗
I know, but I put it back in
这样我才能每天都有指望呀
so I'd have something to look forward to.
老公  怎么还不出来
Bob, where are you?
我再要一小会都不行啊
Can I have a minute?!
行了  赶紧的
Well, hurry up!
你要错过咱家的早餐黄金共聚时刻了
You're missing quality family time!
Gabe  不许再敲烤面包机了
Gabe, stop hitting the toaster.
可这花的时间也忒长了
But it's taking forever.
时间久到我都忘记放进去的是啥了
I don't even remember what I put in here.
好的  Charlie  我马上给你拿果汁来
Okay, Charlie, I will get you your juice in just a minute, honey.
哇塞  连Charlie都在闹脾气
Whoa! Even Charlie's in a mood.
早安
Morning.
老公  你是不是忘了做什么事啊
Bob, did you forget to do something?
我今晚补亲你总行吧
I'll kiss you tonight.
我不是说这个  你刮胡子才刮了一半脸
No. You only shaved half your face.
这样  那样  这样
Pick, pick, pick.
也许我就喜欢这个尊容打扮呢
Maybe this is how I like to wear it now.
得了吧  你看上去可笑极了
Well, it looks ridiculous.
要是我也决定只梳理一边的头发会怎样呢
What if I decided just to brush half my hair?
我以为你早就决定这样了呢
I thought you already made that decision.
好极了  你是不想活了吧
Oh, you are going down!
等等  停下  停下  你们大家听到什么没
Wait! Stop! Stop! Do you guys hear that?
我什么也没听到
I don't hear anything.
正解
Exactly.
狗狗的吠声停止了
The barking stopped.
- 怎么会这样  - 没搞错吧
- Oh, come on!  - Really?
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
Today's all burnt toast
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
Running late, and dad jokes
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
Has anybody seen my left shoe
■
翻译： 山鹰逢羽
我闭上双眼  咬口早餐
I close my eyes, take a bite
跳上车子  放声大笑
Grab a ride, laugh out loud
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
There it is up on the roof
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
I've been there, I've survived
所以听取我的建议
So just take my advice
■
校订  后期： WaitinZ
宝贝  不要放弃
Hang in there, baby,
世界有很多疯狂无奈
Things are crazy
可是我知道你会有美好未来
But I know your future is bright
宝贝  不要放弃
Hang in there, Baby
不要怀疑
There is no maybe
一切终会如你所愿
Eveything turns out all right
生活有悲有喜
Sure life is up and down
可是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
But trust me, it comes back all around
你会喜欢将来的你
You're gonna love who you turn out to be
宝贝  不要放弃
Hang in there, Baby
查莉成长日记  第一季第九集
Good Luck Charlie  S01E09  Up A Tree
还好Charlie至少睡了一小会儿
Well, at least Charlie's getting some sleep.
但是Dabney太太到底为什么非要养那条蠢狗呢
Why did Mrs. Dabney have to get that stupid dog, anyway?
她就不能养点别的少发出点声音的东西吗
Why couldn't she get something that made less noise...
比如说鱼什么的
Like a fish?
鱼根本就不出声
Fish don't make any noise.
那我希望你就是条鱼
I wish you were a fish.
我们是否可以赞成那东西是个有害的动物呢
Can we all agree that thing is a pest?
因为作为灭害专家而言  我有责任
Because as an exterminator, it is my job
去监管任何有害生物
To take care of pests.
当你说“监管”的时候
When you say "take care of,"
我懂得你其实是在说“杀”了它们
I know you actually mean kill.
我声明  你用这个词我完全没意见
Which I'm totally fine with, by the way.
我要过去找Dabney太太 提出要求
I'll just go over to Mrs. Dabney's and demand
让她晚上把狗管好在房子里面
She keep the dog in at night.
或者我们也可以更友善一点
Or we could just try being friendly.
对Dabney太太友善吗
Friendly? With Mrs. Dabney?
这是啥日子哦  奇思妙想节吗
What is this, crazy idea day?
听着  我说真的
Okay, look, I am serious.
不如我今晚邀请她过来
How about I invite her over tonight
到我们家喝咖啡  然后我来烤一个派吧
for a cup of coffee and I bake a pie?
我以为你想妥善解决这件事的
I thought you wanted this to go well.
好吧  我们就去邀请Dabney太太
Okay, we'll have Mrs. Dabney over,
但我希望每个人都要表现出最佳风度
but I want everybody on their best behavior,
特别是你  小先生
especially you, mister.
我不觉得自己拥有什么最佳风度
I don't think I have a best behavior.
那你最好在今晚之前找一个
Yeah, well, you'd better find one before tonight.
为她说句公道话  Dabney太太并不是一直这样的
In her defense, Mrs. Dabney wasn't always like this.
其实她以前蛮好相处的
She actually used to be kind of nice.
那是啥年月啦
When was that?
让我想想  你几岁了
Let's see, how old are you?
好了  派我也吃了
All right, got my pie.
你们有什么要求
What do you want?
我们什么要求也没有  Dabney太太
We don't want anything, Mrs. Dabney.
就是  我们只是想敦行睦邻友好呀
Yeah, we're just being neighborly.
他又做了什么坏事?
What did he do?
我什么坏事也没做
I didn't do anything.
我不喜欢你  Gabe
I don't like you, Gabe.
可我喜欢你呀  Dabney太太
But I like you, Mrs. Dabney.
事实上  我很想“照顾照顾”你
In fact, I'd like to take care of you.
出去
Out.
Dabney太太 你新养了一条狗不是吗
Mrs. Dabney, so you have a new dog...
一只小吉娃娃
A little chihuahua.
原来这就是你们要找的茬子
So that's what this is about.
不是这事儿还能是啥事儿啊
It's not not what this is about.
狗狗是有名字的  他叫赫拉克勒斯（大力神）
Dog's got a name... Hercules.
真好笑  因为啊
That's funny because...
大力神不是要又大又壮的吗
Hercules is like so big and strong
然而你家的小狗却
And your dog is so...
只是要睦邻友好的
Just being neighborly.
你看啊  情况是这样的  你家的大力神好像很爱叫唤
Look, the thing is, Hercules has a tendency to bark...
叫个不停
A lot...
整晚整晚的
All night long.
是啊  所以我们想知道  您能不能
Right, so we were wondering if maybe
晚上就寝前把它放到屋子里去呢
you could bring him in before bedtime.
不行  新鲜空气对狗狗有益
Oh, no! Fresh air's good for dogs.
那睡眠还有益于人类健康呢
Well, sleep is good for people.
我早知道你说的这个理论了
I had that same thought
在贵府上的每个孩子出生后我都感受极深
After every one of your many babies arrived.
我们现在说的是狗
We were talking about the dog.
既然现在是在开牢骚大会
Well, since we're airing our grievances...
我们一直求她不要做那种派的
We begged her not to make that pie.
我要说的是  也许你们可以做点什么
I was gonna say that maybe there's a little something
对我进行补偿
You can do for me.
哦  Dabney太太  我们已经告诉过您了
Oh, Mrs. Dabney, we've already told you,
我们是不会送Gabe去军校的
We're not sending Gabe to military school.
不过如果这个问题真的很严重  我们还是愿意送他
But if it's a deal-breaker, we are willing to send him
去别的地方的
To other places.
我说的是你们后院那棵大橡树
I was talking about your oak tree out back.
那边已经长出老大一个分枝伸到我家院子里了
There's a branch that hangs over my yard
老是往下掉橡子  把我院子里弄的乱七八糟
Always dropping acorns and making a big mess.
哎呀  那没问题
Well, no problem.
小狗进屋  树枝砍掉
Dog goes in, branch comes off.
我们成交不
We got a deal?
成交
We have a deal.
老爸  那根树杈还架着我们的小树屋呢
Dad, that branch holds our treehouse.
那又怎样  你们这些孩子好多年都没爬上去了
Well, so what? You kids haven't been up there in years.
我正迷糊着呢  到底要不要送走Gabe这小子啊
I'm confused. Is Gabe going somewhere or not?
要知道  要是顺便把树屋一起推倒
You know, if that treehouse comes down,
那就最好不过了  因为它在我的菜地花园里挡去了很多阳光
That'll be even better... More sunlight for my vegetable garden.
尽量多吃素  也许能让我的寿命目标
Start eating healthier... Might even make my goal
达到一百岁
Of living to be 100.
Dabney太太  你不想留下来吃完你的派吗
Mrs. Dabney, don't you want to stay and finish your pie?
祝你们晚安了
You have a good night, now.
她走啦  都还没友好地拥抱我一下呢
She's gone? But I didn't get my hug.
好了  至少我们现在总算可以睡个好觉了
Well, at least we'll finally be able to get some sleep.
太可惜我们要失去自己的小树屋了
Too bad we have to lose our treehouse.
我们还有个树屋吗
We have a treehouse?
当然啊
Yeah.
Teddy和我小时候总是爬上去呆着呢
Teddy and I used to go up there all the time when we were little.
就是  我们那时候在上面觉得可快乐了
Yeah, we had so much fun up there.
你俩没说笑吧
Are you kidding me?
你们俩在上面干的事就是打架而已
All you two ever did up there was fight.
我记得的可不是这样  我们有过美好时光的
That's not how I remember it. We had great times.
是的  要我说  除了有几次
Yeah, I mean, except for, you know, all those times
你从窗子掉下去之外
That you fell out the window.
哦  我也很享受那样的时刻的
Oh, I enjoyed those too.
我怎么不知道我们家有个树屋呢
How did I not know we had a treehouse?
呃  因为里面都有点杂草丛生了
Well, 'cause it's kind of overgrown.
是我在我们去夏威夷的那个夏天修起来的
I built it that summer we went to Hawaii.
你们大家还去过夏威夷
You guys went to Hawaii?!
是啊  以前我们做过很多好玩的事的
Yeah. We used to do all kinds of fun stuff.
那从何时开始你们就不再寻欢作乐了
When did that stop?
那就看看你有多大了呗
Well, how old are you?
看看这个呀  小Charlie
Check it out, Charlie.
这就是我们的老树屋
Here's our old treehouse.
快看  这是那套旧的喝茶游戏道具
Oh, look. Here's your old tea party set
还有我们以前下的棋
And all our board games.
呀  等等  快瞧瞧这个
Oh! Wait... And look at this.
那些东西叫做中国指套
These are the Chinese handcuffs
PJ小时候经常把手指卡在里面
That pj always used to get stuck in.
喂  帮帮我好吗
Uh... A little help?
哦  波波宝宝
Oh! Baby booboo!
我的天哪  我还以为我把她弄丢了呢
Oh my goodness, I thought I lost her.
都过去好多年了
It's been so many years.
看来她经历了苦难的年月啊
And those years have not been kind.
对了  我想起来了  以前我总是在这儿玩过家家
Yeah, I remember. I used to come up here
假装波波是个真宝宝
And pretend booboo was a real baby.
我是个特别棒的小妈妈  不是吗
I was a very good mother, huh?
直到你把你的宝宝丢在树屋里  一丢就是十年
Until you left your baby in a treehouse for 10 years.
咦  看这儿
Oh, whoa, look!
你在这墙上刻了什么字
Here's something you carved into the wall.
PJ爱PB  谁是PB啊
"P.J. hearts P.B." Who's P.B.?
花生酱呀
Peanut butter.
那可是纯真年代啊
It was a simpler time.
你知道最糟是什么事嘛
You know what stinks?
嗯  当他们往里面加了果冻之后
When they premix it with the jelly.
不是啊  最糟就是小Charlie再也不能
No, it stinks that Charlie's never gonna
到这个树屋上来玩了
get to use this treehouse.
她很可能会爱上这里的呀
She'd probably love it up here.
喂  孩子们  快下来吧
Hey, kids! Come on down now!
PJ  我们要为Charlie挽救这个地方
P.J., we have to save this place for Charlie.
好吧  我也希望可以  但老爸做了个交易
Well, I wish we could, but Dad made a deal.
那又怎样  交易就是用来打破的
Yeah well, deals are made to be broken.
说的对
Right!
黄金守则啊
The golden rule!
- 喂  孩子们  - 嗯  老爸
- Hey, kids!  - Hey, Dad!
我们改变主意了  我们一点也不想失去这个小树屋
We changed our minds. We don't want to lose the treehouse after all.
太迟了  我都已经和别人说定了
It's too late. I already shook hands on it.
难道我们就不能再商量一下么
Well, can we at least talk about this?
对啊  也许我们应该进行家庭投票表决
Yeah, maybe take a family vote?
家庭又不是民主政体啥的  伙计们
This isn't a democracy, guys.
而且就算是你想那样做
And by the way, even if it was,
手上持家伙的人
The guy with the chainsaw
一定总是能赢的
Always wins.
够了  快下来吧
Come on. Come on down.
不要
No!
竟敢不要
No?
就是不要  我们才不会离开呢
No, we're not leaving.
是的  我们要守在这里保卫它
Yeah! We're staying right here.
我们要向霸权开战
We're fighting the power!
马上给我下来  否则就关你们禁闭
Get down here now or you're grounded!
当人家根本没有呆在地面上的时候  你是不能关他禁闭的
You can't ground someone who's not actually on the ground.
对  PJ说的好  向霸权开战
Yeah! Right on, P.J. Fight the power!
告诉你们吧  小鬼
You know what?
试试看来向大锯子开战好了
Good luck fighting the power saw!
无论怎样  你们总之是要乖乖下来的
You're coming down one way or another!
不  我们不会下去  历史上有我们学习的榜样
No, we are not, okay? We have history on our side!
我们将要进行“非暴力不合作运动”
We are going to protest peacefully
就像甘地和马丁·路德·金一样
Like gandhi and martin luther king.
他有一个梦想
He had a dream.
是么  那我也有一个梦想  Teddy
Yeah well, I got a dream too, Teddy...
我想睡个好觉
To get some sleep!
你是不会吓住我们的
You're not scaring us.
对  我们会蔑笑你的
No! We laugh at you!
好吧  知道不  小鬼们
All right, you know what?
我受够这一团糟了  我要启用重型武器了
I'm done messing around. I'm bringing out the big guns.
对  就是请出你们的老妈
That's right... Mom!
尽管去叫呀
You go get Mom.
就是  她也吓不倒我们的
Yeah, she doesn't scare us!
不妙啊  他要去请出老妈了
This is bad, he's getting Mom.
快关上  别让她上来
Lock her up.
快出去把你的小孩从树上叫下来
Go out there and get your kids out of that tree.
行啊  为啥每次他们不听你的话时
Okay, why are they always my kids
就都变成“我的”小孩啦
when they won't do what you want?
他们正在搞什么静坐抗议
They're having some kind of sit-in
想要拯救那个树屋呢
to try and save the treehouse.
我是很欣赏他们立场明确的态度
Now, I appreciate that they're taking a stand.
但我不高兴的是他们是在抗议我
I just don't like that it's against me!
你能不能先冷静一下
Would you calm down?
可我是父亲大人
But I'm the father!
我本该掌控这一切的
I'm in charge around here!
是说当你不在家的时候
When you're not home.
亲爱的  你根本就是无中生有瞎操心
Honey, you are getting upset over nothing.
我们现在谈的是Teddy和PJ这两个孩子
This is Teddy and P.J. We're talking about.
他俩都不可能在同一个房间里呆满五分钟
They can't be in the same room for five minutes
和平相处不吵吵  那是不可能的
Without getting into a fight.
他们在上面坚持不到一个小时的啦
They won't last an hour up there.
那好吧
All right.
不过等他们下来后  一定要因为挑战我的权威而得到惩罚
But when they come down, they're getting punished for defying me!
如果您同意的话
If that's okay with you.
我累了
I'm tired.
我觉得冷啊
I'm cold.
我们还要在这里居“高”不下保持多久啊
How much longer can we keep this up?
我们在这上面刚呆了十二分钟而已
We've been up here for 12 minutes.
要是我早知道我们要进行抗议活动的话
If I had known we were gonna protest,
我会事先有所准备的
I would have prepared.
首先  我肯定就不会去喝那罐
For one thing, I wouldn't have had
特大号装的根汁汽水了
That extra-large root beer.
好了  试着专心想着我们为什么要这样做
All right, let's just stay focused on why we're here...
是为了Charlie啊
For Charlie.
那样想可没用
That doesn't help.
Charlie总是想什么时候尿就什么时候尿
Charlie gets to pee whenever she wants
-所以我才会想到这个  -好吧  你就不用再告诉我
- Which is why my idea... - Okay, please don't tell me
那个什么“给青少年的尿不湿”创意了
About diaper-for-teens again.
嘿  Gabe
Hey, Gabe.
嘿
Hey.
那么  这就是我以前从不晓得的传说中的树屋啊
So, this is the famous treehouse I never knew about.
想参加我们的静坐抗议吗
Want to join our sit-in?
就好像甘地和比莉·琼·金（前著名网球选手）
It's just like when Gandhi and Billie Jean King
他俩混双组队  为了南北战争的停战抗议
teamed up to stop the civil war.
妈呀  刚才那句话的每一个单词都错得离谱
Almost every word in that sentence was wrong.
你觉得怎样  Gabe老弟  你要参加吗
What do you say, Gabe? Are you in?
我参加
I'm in.
- 太好了  - 棒极了
- Great.  - Yeah!
不过首先  你要去给我们运送一些补给来
But first, you'll need to bring us some supplies,
只是一些必需品就好
Just the essentials.
零食啊  我的电动游戏  还有我的吉他
Snacks, my video games, my guitar...
喂  公子哥  这可是静坐
Whoa, dude, this is a sit-in,
不是搬家
Not a move-in.
还要一些花生酱
Oh! And some peanut butter.
嘿  没错  我对它的爱恋可没结束呢
Yeah, that's right, the love affair continues.
好的  我去去就来
Well, I'll be back.
你要去干什么
What are you doing?
我是要去加入静坐抗议
I'm gonna join the sit-in.
我也要为真理而战
I have to do what's right.
不如我带你出去吃冰激凌怎么样
How about I take you out for ice cream instead?
那我先去车里等
I'll be in the car.
我们以前经常玩的那个疯狂的扑克玩法
What was that crazy card game
叫什么来着  要用到所有的8
We used to play with all the eights?
不就叫“疯8牌”吗
Crazy eights.
不对
No
Gabe怎么还没带零食上来呢
Where is Gabe with the snacks?
现在连我都觉得饿了
Now I'm getting hungry.
饿惨了
So hungry.
我老觉得我闻到烤牛排的香味了
I keep thinking I smell steak cooking.
就是  我也闻到了
Yeah, me too.
真的吗
Really?
哎哟喂
Oh, hey!
可别怪我哦  我在给全家人做晚餐呢
Don't mind me... Just making dinner for my family...
我说的是在地面上的家人
You know, the ones on the ground.
得了吧  我们很清楚你的意图
Yeah, okay. We know what you're doing
那不会管用的
And it's not gonna work.
那好  随便你们吧
Well, suit yourself.
不过我现在正要烤一块五分熟的
But I'm making one medium rare
我可知道某人最喜欢这嫩度了
The way I know someone likes.
我最喜欢五分熟了  他在引诱我呢
I like medium rare. He's talking about me.
要坚强
Stay strong.
现在我要离开一小会
Now, I'm gonna be right back.
我要进屋去了
I'm going inside the house
要去看看我那巧克力蛋奶酥哦
To check on my chocolate souffle.
你那套把戏别人也会玩
Two can play at this game!
说的是  除非我们也有烧烤炉和牛排啊
Yeah, if we had a barbecue and some steaks.
一天最重要的晚餐就要到手了  T骨牛排啊
Catch of the day... T-Bone.
好极了
Yes!
- 来吧  -别 别 别
- Okay.  - No, no, no!
你肯定没办法勾住T字排骨  还是去钓肉片好了
You'll never get the T-Bone. Go for the filet.
我想我钓到了  勾住啦  勾住啦
I think I got it. I got it! I got it!
我从没像现在这样爱你
I have never loved you more than...
你这白痴
Idiot!
我看有人把他们的鱼竿烤过头了哦
I think somebody overcooked their fishing pole.
这个看上去更像过熟了嘛
This looks more medium well.
我饿死了
I'm so hungry!
这上面一点吃的都没有
And there's nothing to eat up here.
好像还是有的  橡子 橡子也是食物  对吗
Or is there? Acorns... Acorns are food, right?
那是松鼠的食物还差不多
For squirrels.
松鼠是怎么把这玩意剥开的
How do squirrels do this.
因为它们是松鼠
Well, they're squirrels.
你知道不
You know what?
我受够了  我要退出
I can't take this anymore. I'm done.
等等  别这样
Wait, no!
你就这样放弃吗  一如你的本性
You're just giving up? That is so like you!
什么叫我的“本性”
What is so like me?
总是半途而废
To be a quitter.
是么  好吧  你总是很专横
Yeah? Well, you're bossy!
我一点都不专横
I am not bossy!
你以后不许再那么说我  我命令你
And don't you ever call me that again. I forbid you!
- 法西斯 - 废才
- Bossy!  - Quitty!
哟  你这也算成熟吗
Oh, real mature!
我可比你成熟多了
I am more mature than you are!
随你怎么说  哇呀  够了
Whatever! Oh! Okay!
够了
Okay!
行了  快把棒子放下
All right, drop the bat
不然波波宝就要变成烤宝宝了
Or baby booboo becomes baby barbecue.
我不信你有那个胆子
You wouldn't dare!
那就试试啊
Try me.
把娃娃给我
Give me the baby.
把棒子给我
Give me the bat.
娃娃
The baby.
棒子
The bat
PJ
P.J.!
拉我上去  拉我上去
Pull me up! Pull me up!
哦  等等  你还要退出吗
Oh, wait! Are you quitting?
啥
What?
你知道的  假如说
You know, like,
我要是拉你上来了  你还要不要继续静坐抗议呢
If I pull you back in, will you keep doing the sit-in?
既然我另一个选择是脸对着烧烤炉
Since my alternative is a face-first dive
直冲冲的掉下去  那么答案是  继续
into a hot barbecue... Yes!
还有一件事
One more thing.
你必须无条件给我当司机
You have to drive me wherever I want to go
之后一整个月都要这样
For the next month.
成交
Deal.
现在快拉我上去  我的脸都要变成炭了
Now pull me up,my face is browning.
好吧
Okay.
多谢你救了我
Thank you for saving me.
不客气
No problem.
可是啊  本来你也不用去救我的
Although, you wouldn't have had to save me
还不是你先把我推出去的
If you didn't push me out of a treehouse!
哇哇哇  喂 喂  快停下
Whoa whoa whoa! Hey hey! Stop!
哇  休战  休战
Whoa! Truce! Truce!
天啊  咱俩是咋啦  我们好像还是七岁的小孩子一样
Gosh, what is wrong with us? We're going at it like seven-year-olds.
老妈说的对
Mom was right.
在这上面我们确实一直在打架  不是吗
We did fight up here all the time, didn't we?
对啊  而且到现在都没变  我们还在继续打呢
Yes, and nothing's changed. We're still doing it.
难道我们俩就要一直这样相处下去吗
Is this the way it's always gonna be between us?
我希望不是
I hope not.
我可不想以后坐在养老院的走廊上
I don't want to be sitting on the porch
还要挥舞着泡沫棒子
Of our old folks' home whacking each other
互相打来打去
With foam bats.
哦  难道我们必须住在同一家养老院吗
Oh, do we have to live in the same old folks' home?
PJ  如果我们不能同心协力
P.J., if we can't come together
哪怕仅仅是为小Charlie做一件事
And do this one thing for Charlie,
那我们就更不可能一起做得成其他任何事了
We're never gonna come together on anything.
你说的对
You're right.
我们一定可以做成这件事的  为了Charlie
We can do this... For Charlie.
为了Charlie
For Charlie.
那么
So...
那你现在想干什么
What do you want to do now?
我不知道
I don't know.
真希望我们可以快点成功挽救这个小树屋
I wish we could hurry up and save this treehouse
这样我们才能尽早从这鬼地方出去
So we could get the heck out of this treehouse.
他们还呆在那树上呢
They're still up in that tree.
你不是说他俩这会儿该下来了吗
You said they'd be down by now.
这个嘛  我是那样想来着
Well, I thought they would be.
为啥我这块牛扒上有一个塑料钩子呢
Why is there a plastic hook in my steak?
别吃下去就行
Eat around it.
其实  仔细想想这事儿
You know, when you think about it,
这还挺不错的  我是说  Teddy和PJ这俩孩子
This is actually kind of nice. I mean, Teddy and P.J.
总算能同心合力一起做点事儿了  我很为他们自豪
Are finally working together on something. I'm proud of them.
你到底站在哪边啊
Whose side are you on,
我党还是叛乱分子
Ours or the rebels?
你管叫他们“叛乱分子”
The rebels?
得了  你应该晓得
Okay, you realize
这又不是真的战争  对吧
We're not actually at war, right?
我当然知道
Of course I do.
因为如果是那样的话  必须有人先发表一份
For that to happen, someone would have to issue
正式的宣战宣言
A formal declaration of war...
嗯  就是这会儿应该已经打印出来的那张
Which should almost be done printing out.
老公  他们正按着我们教育他们的精神去做事
Bob, they're doing exactly what we taught them to do.
他们为了自己的信念而坚持立场
They're standing up for what they believe in.
好了  你知道不  我们现在得教他们另一套了
Well, you know what? Now we're going to teach them
不要把老爹惹毛了
Don't mess with Daddy.
Gabe  去把你的充水气球弹弓拿来
Gabe, go get your water balloon launcher.
好啊
Okay.
Gabe  坐下
Gabe, sit.
老公  你这样就有点过头了
Bob, you're taking this too far.
我并没有  还有我已经给你下了命令了  先生
No I'm not. And I gave you an order, mister.
Gabe  不许走
Gabe, stand down.
不好意思  老爸  不过我更怕妈妈一些
Sorry, Dad, but I'm a little more afraid of Mom.
好吧  我就孤军作战好了
Fine. I'll fight this battle myself.
嘿  小甜心  你不是真的怕我吧
Hey, sweetheart, you're not really afraid of me, are you?
有点儿
A little.
那很好
Good.
我给你们最后一次机会让你们下来
I'm giving you one last chance to come down!
好的  我明白了
Okay! All right!
我也不想诉诸武力  不过这都是你们逼的
I don't like doing this, but you've forced my hand!
哦  怎么会这样  你们够走运的
Oh, come on! So lucky!
你们走狗屎运了  知道不  小鬼们
You got so lucky! You know what?
下一发炮弹可就要直直地穿进窗子啦
Next one's coming right through the window!
是吗  吃我一弹
Oh, yeah? Take that!
你怎么也上去了
What are you doing?
向强权开战
Fightin' the power!
可我们是掌权者啊
But we're the power.
孩子们是对的  小树屋应该被保留
The kids are right. This treehouse is worth saving.
这里乱糟糟的到底闹腾啥呢
What is going on over here?
这可真不是聊天的好时间  Dabney太太
You know, this really isn't a good time, Mrs. Dabney.
你最好去好好地驾驭自己的家人
You'd better get a handle on that family of yours
因为就目前而看  似乎他们不把你当回事
'Cause right now, it looks like they're kicking your butt.
劳您大驾  你能让我自己处理这事儿吗  行吗
Would you let me deal with this, please?
最好快点  因为大力神觉得有点寂寞
You'd better, 'cause hercules is getting kinda lonely.
我正考虑再多养一只狗呢
I'm thinking of getting another dog.
你现在是要威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
再弄一只母狗来
This one's gonna be female...
他们可能还能生一窝狗宝宝呢
Might even have some puppies.
这就对了
That's right.
你去把他们弄下来
You go get them down.
该是展现一家之主威力的时候啦
Time to put on the big pants!
他要上来啦
He's coming up.
我们必须拦截他
We have to stop him.
不要开火
Hold your fire!
小心
Careful,
这可能是个陷阱
This could be a trick.
我是求和来的  我要加入反抗组织
I come in peace. I've come to join the resistance.
太好了  好耶
All right! Yeah!
就是这样  Dabney太太
That's right, Mrs. Dabney!
我不在乎你的狗呢  爱咋咋地
I don't care about your dog!
我确实要释放威力了
Oh, the big pants are on
但这是为了捍卫我的家人们
And they're staying up here with my family.
胜利啦  解放啦
We did it! Yes!
你将拥有一个小树屋了  Charlie
You can have a treehouse, Charlie.
会度过好长好长的美好时光的
For a long long time.
那是什么声音
What was that?
等一下  我们是不是所有人都爬上去然后超载了
Wait, have we ever all been up here at the same time?
大家都没事吗
Is everyone okay?
- 还好 - 没问题
- Yeah... - I think so.
哇  看啊
Whoa, look!
哦  小宝贝
Oh, hon!
非要搞得那么惊天动地吗
Was that so hard?
有成就感嘛
Yeah.
好了  树屋已经倒了
Well, the treehouse is down.
那么  你今晚就该把狗领进屋  对吧
So, you're gonna be bringing your dog in tonight, right?
哎呀  大力神其实不是我的狗
Oh, hercules doesn't belong to me.
我只是帮别人照看两天而已
I was just dogsitting for a couple of days.
其实人家是爱猫族
I'm a cat person...
同时是一个牛逼的谈判家
And an excellent negotiator.
不要扔那个水球
Do not throw that balloon.
我们用这个弹弓射过去  儿子
We're gonna launch that balloon, mister.
老爸
Dad!
看呀  Charlie  老爸和你的哥哥们
Well, Charlie, Dad and the boys
正在给你造一个新的树屋呢
Are building you a new treehouse.
这样以后你就能爬上去和自己的波波宝宝玩了
So someday you can go up there and play with baby booboo,
你知道吧  只要我们能找到她的头就行
You know, just as soon as we find her head.
现在嘛  她就是一个网球头娃娃  耶
Right now, she's baby tennis ball. Yeah!
哎呀  这可没啥乐的
No, not as much fun.
哦  还有我要建议你最好给小树屋立下规定
Oh, and I want to recommend that you make the treehouse
禁止男生进入
No boys allowed...
特别是如果那个男生的体重和老爸差不多
Especially if that boy weighs as much as Dad,
因为要是你让他上去了  那可就惨了
because if you do let him up there,
好了  祝你好运了  小Charlie
well, good luck, Charlie.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
Gabe说他怕妈妈比怕我更多一些
Gabe says he's more scared of Mom than he is of me.
所以我要来吓唬吓唬他
So I'm going to scare him.
嘿哟  老爸
Hey, Dad!
Gabe宝贝  你做完功课了吗
Gabe, honey, did you finish your homework?
哎呀呀  恐怖老妈驾到
Ah... Mummy mom.
你知道自己哪方面不行了吧
You'd got it all you don't.